https://www.re-cycle.org/privacy-policy/

Privacy Policy - Re-Cycle
!! Bike Drop Pop Up Events - See News & Events for more information !!
Privacy Policy
How we respect privacy when we deal with personal information collected by our organisation.This Privacy Policy applies to information we, Re-Cycle, collect about individuals who interact with our organisation. It explains what personal information we collect and how we use it.If you have any comments or questions about this notice, feel free to contact us at info@re-cycle.org, or Claire Kettle, Re-Cycle’s Chief Privacy Officer or 01206 617865.1. Personal data that we processThe following explains the types of data we collect and the legal basis, under current data protection legislation, on which this data is processed.Purpose: Enquiring about our organisation and its workData: (key elements): Name, email, messageBasis: Legitimate interests – it is necessary for us to read and store your message so that we can respond in the way that you would expect.Purpose: Subscribing to email updates about our workData: (key elements):  Name, email,Basis: Consent – you have given your active consent.Purpose: Making a donation or buying a bikeData: (key elements):  Name, email, address, payment informationBasis:  Legitimate interests – this information is necessary for us to fulfill your intention of donating money and your expectation of receiving a confirmation message.Purpose: Donating a bikeData: (key elements):  Name, email, phone numberBasis:  Legitimate interests – it is necessary for us to read and store your message so that we can respond in the way that you would expect, including arranging collection of a bike if required.Purpose: Website functionalityData: (key elements):  Website activity collected through cookiesBasis:  Legitimate interests – it is necessary for us to store a small amount of information, usually through cookies, to deliver functionality that you would expect, such as remembering the contents of your order before you have fully completed the process.  2.    How we use your dataWe will only use your data in a manner that is appropriate considering the basis on which that data was collected, as set out in the table at the top of this policy.For example, we may use your personal information to:• reply to enquiries you send to us;• handle donations or other transactions that you initiate;• where you have specifically agreed to this, send you marketing communications by email relating to our work which we think may be of interest to you. 3.    When we share your dataWe will only pass your data to third parties in the following circumstances:• you have provided your explicit consent for us to pass data to a named third party;• we are using a third party purely for the purposes of processing data on our behalf and we have in place a data processing agreement with that third party that fulfils our legal obligations in relation to the use of third party data processors; or• we are required by law to share your data.In addition, we will only pass data to third parties outside of the EU where appropriate safeguards are in place as defined by Article 46 of the General Data Protection Regulation. 4.    How long we keep your dataWe take the principles of data minimisation and removal seriously and have internal policies in place to ensure that we only ever ask for the minimum amount of data for the associated purpose and delete that data promptly once it is no longer required.Where data is collected on the basis of consent, we will seek renewal of consent at least every three years. 5.    Rights you have over your dataYou have a range of rights over your data, which include the following:• Where data processing is based on consent, you may revoke this consent at any time and we will make it as easy as possible for you to do this (for example by putting ‘unsubscribe’ links at the bottom of all our marketing emails).• You have the right to ask for rectification and/or deletion of your information.• You have the right of access to your information.• You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner if you feel your rights have been infringed.A full summary of your legal rights over your data can be found on the Information Commissioner’s website here: https://ico.org.uk/If you would like to access the rights listed above, or any other legal rights you have over your data under current legislation, please get in touch with us.Please note that relying on some of these rights, such as the right to deleting your data, will make it impossible for us to continue to deliver some services to you. However, where possible we will always try to allow the maximum access to your rights while continuing to deliver as many services to you as possible. 6.    Cookies & usage trackingA cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that is downloaded on to your computer when you visit a website. Cookies are used by many websites and can do a number of things, eg remembering your preferences, recording what you have put in your shopping basket, and counting the number of people looking at a website.Where cookies are used to collect personal data, we list these purposes in section 1 above, along with other personal data that we collect. However, we also use some cookies that do not collect personal information but that do help us collect anonymous information about how people use our website. We use Google Analytics for this purpose.  Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website usage by means of cookies, which are stored on users’ computers. The information collected by Google Analytics about usage of our website is not personally identifiable. The data is collected anonymously, stored by Google and used by us to create reports about website usage. Google’s privacy policy is available at https://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html. 7.    ModificationsWe may modify this Privacy Policy from time to time and will publish the most current version on our website. If a modification meaningfully reduces your rights, we’ll notify people whose personal data we hold and is affected.1.
Sign Up For Our Newsletter
Keep up to date with all will the latest news, bike sales, events and fundraising.
Subscribe
By supporting Re-Cycle, you will be helping us to continue changing lives; one pedal turn at a time.
Chris Boardman, Patron
Support Us Today
Unit 8 The Grove Estate,Colchester Road, Wormingford,Colchester, Essex CO6 3AJ 01206 617 865
Facebook
Twitter
Youtube
Instagram
All Rights Reserved | Copyright © 2020 | Privacy Policy | Cookie Policy | T&C’s | Registered Charity Number: 1063570 Registered Company
